

Europass Curriculum Vitae



Personal information

First name(s) / Surname(s)

Ashish Kumar Basak

Address(es)

House: Via Della Resistenza 64, Int H, Spre, Povo 38123 Trento, Italy

Telephone(s)

Mobile: +393270470305

E-mail

ashish021@gmail.com ashish_kbit@skype.com

Skype

Bangladeshi

Nationality

28/12/1983

Date of birth Gender

Male

Career Objectives

To make the best use of my technical expertise in logic development & data analysis in a research based career; hence to acquire and apply advanced knowledge in a particular field, "Machine learning", "Semantic Web", "Human Computer Interaction"

Research Interest **Desired Employment**

Machine Learning, Knowledge Management, Formal Methods Research Associate, Software Engineer

Work experience

Dates

19th June, 2012 - 19th December, 2012

Occupation or position held

Software Developer

Main activities and responsibilities

- Responsible for development of new programs, analyzes current programs and processes, and making recommendations which yield a more cost effective product.
- Writes, edits, and debugs new computer programs for assigned projects, including necessary records and desired output
- Research and recommend software tools to management

Name and address of employer Type of business or sector Home on Line Web S.r.I, Via Lazzaretto, 19, Milano, Italy. Web: www.homeonline.it

E-commerce, Document service provider

Dates

1st August, 2007 - 31st July, 2010

Occupation or position held Main activities and responsibilities Senior Software Engineer

- Designing, coding and debugging applications in various software languages.
- Software analysis, code analysis, requirements analysis, software review, identification of code metrics, system risk analysis, software reliability analysis.
- Object-oriented Design and Analysis (OOA and OOD)
- Software modeling and simulation
- Front end graphical user interface design
- Performance tuning, improvement, balancing, usability, automation

Name and address of employer Type of business or sector Noocleus Media Bangladesh Limited, Dhaka, Bangladesh. Web: www.noocleusmedia.com

Software Development & IT Service Provider

Page 1/3 - Curriculum vitae of Basak Ashish Kumar

Education and training

Dates

September, 2010 - March, 2013

Title of qualification awarded Principal subjects covered Master of Science in Computer Science
Major: Software Technologies

Name and type of organisation providing education and training

Università degli Studi di Trento, Trento, Italy.

Master Thesis

32123, Trento, italy

"Entity Integration via Semantic Entity Matching"

Dates

tes | March, 2002 - March, 2006

Title of qualification awarded

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

Principal subjects covered

Major: Software Engineering

Name and type of organisation providing education and training

Khulna University of Engineering and Technology (KUET)

Undergraduate Thesis 4

9203, Khulna, Bangladesh

"Further Compression of JPEG Images for Multimedia Communication"

Dates

April, 2012 - June, 2012

Title of qualification awarded Principal occupational skills covered

Software Developer as stage/Intern

- Develop software modules according to the specifications
- Document software modules developed by the trainee
- Participate in system test and system integration
- Debugging software modules

Name and type of organisation providing education and training

Fondazione Bruno Kessler (FBK); www.fbk.eu Via Sommarive 18, Povo 38050 Trento, Italy

Personal skills and competences

Mother tongue(s)

Other language(s)

Self-assessment

European level (*)

English Italian Hindi

Bengali

	Understanding				Speaking				Writing	
	Listening	Reading		Spoken interaction		Spoken production				
C2	Proficient user	C2	Proficient user	C2	Proficient user	C2	Proficient user	C2	Proficient user	
A1	Independent user	A1	Independent user	A1	Basic user	A1	Basic user	A1	Basic user	

(*) Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Computer skills & competences

Programming languages

Scripting languages (web)

PHP, Perl, Ruby on Rails, Coldfusion, AJAX, XML, HTML, VBScript, JavaScript

Database server

Oracle8i/9i/10g over Linux/ Sun Solaris, MS SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Social skills and competences

- Good problem solver.
- Have strong organization and communication skills.
- A good team worker, flexible, can work under pressure.
- Well-mannered, smart, structured, disciplined, punctual.
- Have good IT, computing and internet skills.
- Able to work across the cultures and organizational boundaries.
- Good communication skills.

Other skills

- Travelling, Mountain-Trekking, Hiking, Biking
- Playing Football, Cricket and Table Tennis, Volleyball etc

Additional information

Projects Conducted/Developed at Post-Graduate level:

- As the requirement of the Course 'Computer Security', Performed requirements &
 organizational model analysis, risk assessment analysis, defining access control model and
 security policy & Architecture and Enforcement Mechanism for post issuance software update
 of smart cards.
- As the requirement of the Course 'Requirement Engineering', conducted project, Conducting Feasibility Study on online real estate marketplace, Modelling Class, Use Case, Sequence and State Diagrams, Identifying Software Requirements Specification. Using Si* and ASTAH.
- As the requirement of the Course 'Network Security', Developed java based secure social network client for smart phone (android).
- As the requirement of the Course 'Laboratory of the service design and engineering', develop various soap and restful web services using JAXWS, Dozer, and EJB with MySQL database.
- As the requirement of the course 'Formal Methods' simulate the various problems and test using NuSMV and SPIN Model checker.

Courses Conducted at Post-Graduate level:

Mathematical Logics, Logics for Data and Knowledge Representation, Formal methods, Programming Languages: Semantics, Computational Complexity, Computability, concurrency Theory, Agent Oriented Software Engineering, Computer Security, Network Security, Requirement Engineering, Human Computer Interaction, Laboratory of Service Design and Engineering

Academic awards

- Full Academic Scholarships for Masters of Science study; that includes the full waiver of the tuition fee and covers living expenses for full 2.5 years. Awarded by: Opera Universitaria di Trento, Provincia Autonoma di Trento, Italy on behalf of University of Trento.
- Received Scholarship from Bangladesh Scholarship Council (BSC), Dhaka, Bangladesh Scholarship, 2002-2003
- Merit Scholarship for Bachelor of Science & Engineering study based on Academic Results from Khulna University of Engineering & Technology (KUET), Bangladesh 2002-2005

References

Available upon request.